DANIEL CARLMAN

Chicago IL · (773) 980-5343 daniel.v.carlman@gmail.com · <u>LinkedIn</u>· <u>GitHub</u>

Front-End Developer based in Chicago IL. I work with React and I'm passionate about responsiveness and web accessibility. I graduated in Economics and worked as a financial analyst and also as a translator before finding my passion in software development. I'm currently being mentored by Senior Developer Farzad YousefZadeh (Epic Games).

PROJECTS

JOBS 4 JUNIORS (WORK IN PROGRESS)

Jobs 4 Juniors fetches jobs from We Work Remotely and shows only those suitable for entry level and intermediate developers. Next steps: improving accessibility and implementing pagination and other quality of life features.

URL: https://jobs4juniors.netlify.app/

Github: https://github.com/danielcarlman/jobs4juniors

REACT SKILL CALCULATOR

React Skill Calculator is something I wish existed when I first started coding. With RSC, I aim to help beginners determine what they need to learn before working with React. The website is responsive and accessible for visually impaired keyboard users.

URL: https://reactskillcalculator.netlify.app/

Github: https://github.com/danielcarlman/skillcalculator

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2019 – APRIL 2020 FRONT-END DEVELOPER, ALTERBANK

Building and maintaining stable, scalable, reusable and easy-to-read codebases with React. Adding new features to the website and the mobile app using ReactJS and React Native (Expo). Implementing mobile-friendly design specifications with CSS, Styled Components and SASS. Integrating Front-End and Back-End with RESTful APIs using Axios.

SEPTEMBER 2016 – OCTOBER 2019
FREELANCE TRANSLATOR, UPWORK.

Translated books, games, songs and documents (English to Brazilian Portuguese).

Upwork profile URL: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~019392ae807e3e88f8

FEB 2016 - MAY 2016

INVESTOR RELATIONS FINANCIAL ANALYST, OI S.A.

Filing of CVM (Brazil's SEC) financial documents. Organizing the team budget and paying suppliers. Preparing and ensuring adherence to technical specifications of services and managing contracts. Creating and translating all necessary material for quarterly and annual results presentations, Q&A events, press releases and CEO speech. Writings reports about investor perception and also financial market analysis comparing the company with its peers in the telecommunications sector.

ARTICLES

JANUARY 2020

INTERVIEW FOR MENTORCRUISE

I talk about my career in tech and my experience as a mentee in this interview conducted by MentorCruise's CEO Dominic Monn.

URL: https://mentorcruise.com/blog/my-mentor-helps-me-think-senior-developer/

AUGUST 2020

DEV.TO ARTICLE

I wrote an article about accessibility called "Improving React Accessibility with Dynamic Aria Label Props" for Dev.to.

URL: https://dev.to/danielcarlman/improving-react-accessibility-with-dynamic-aria-label-props-jl7

EDUCATION

2020

MENTORCRUISE: MENTORSHIP WITH SR. DEVELOPER FARZAD YOUSEFZADEH.

2019

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ECONOMICS, RIO DE JANEIRO STATE UNIVERSITY

SKILLS

- HTML5
- Styling: CSS, SASS, CSS Grid, CSS Flexbox, Media Queries and Styled Components
- UI Components: ChakraUI
- Version control: Git (GitHub and SourceTree)
- Integration: RESTful APIs (Axios and Postman).
- Unit Testing: Test Driven Development (Jest)
- Soft Skills: clear communication, resilience, adaptability and initiative

- JavaScript (+ES6)
- React (with Hooks)
- React Native (Expo)
- Redux
- Project Management: JIRA, Trello
- Idioms: English (fluent), Portuguese (native) and Spar